João Guilherme Barbosa

Full Stack Developer

Contact Info

Novo Hamburgo / RS, Brazil

+ 55 51 99156 2777 joaogbarbosa@gmail.com

About

I'm passionate about solving any technological challenge so I am always refreshing my knowledge in order to learn modern technologies and frameworks.

Developer with over 12 years of experience working with websites, eCommerces, systems, and App.

Other areas of interest are smart home and devices, marketing digital and startup development.

Experience

Codzen / Founder, Full Stack Developer

November 2013 - Present, Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

I have founded Codzen because I observed the necessity of advertising agencies in improving technology release.

- Development of projects in the most diverse technologies and frameworks PHP, HTML, Javascript, C#, Angular, React, Wordpress, Codelgniter, Magento and etc;
- Working for national and international clients such as Dell, Latam, Vivo, Disney, Thyssen Krupp, BTG Pactual, Stihl, Mizuno;
- Supplier and internal team management;
- Responsible for sales and partnership developments.

Algo Poker (Startup initiative - In progresse MVP) / React && React Native Developer

Feberaury - Present

Algo Poker is a mnemonic teaching startup for concepts from basic to advanced poker.

- I worked on the initial project structure with React Native + Redux;
- Build a management system for students, courses, modules, and questions;
- Application development for iOS and Android;
- Continuous integration, improvements, new features, and bug fixes;
- Write developer test cases.

BRA Marketing Digital / Fullstack Developer and Tech Lead

May 2012 - August 2013

Technical Leader of web development teams that used mainly: Magento, Wordpress, HTML, PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL and CSS.

- Responsible for creating standards of development;
- Analysis and budgeting of projects;
- Liaising between the Project manager and tech team;
- Responsible for guaranteeing of projects;
- Reference point in team development;
- Creation of standard CMS and constant integration;
- Technical interview with candidates.

Brivia / Web Developer

March 2009 - December 2011

Brivia is one of the largest digital agencies in Brazil.

- Responsible for creating standards of development;
- Development and analysis of systems in .NET and PHP;
- I worked with multinational clients such as Gerdau, LATAM, Thyssen Krupp;
- Experience of CMMI level 2 certification.

Education

Udacity / React Developer

2018-2019

React, Redux and React Native Developer.

Fundação Escola Técnica Liberato Salzano Vieira da Cunha /

Information Technology and Software Development

2012 - 2013

Technician in development of software with emphasan is in C # and Java

Awards

Globo.com / Hackinpoa - Best Mobile App

2015

Hackathon conducted by globo.com at the opening of the new office. The "Bota na conta" won the event as the best mobile project. By connecting the restaurant owners with the clients, the objective of the APP is reducing the time of waiting once the order and payment can be done by using the APP.

https://glo.bo/2ZRw1yD